<?xml version="1.0"?>
<Grammar xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
		 xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" 
		 xsi:type="AssignmentGrammar">
	<name>Campfire Events</name>
	<author>Lance Boudreaux</author>
	<description>Generates random events that can occur while a party of adventurers are in camped</description>
	<url>http://zenithgames.blogspot.com/2013/06/200-random-campfire-events.html</url>
	<tags>
		<tag>Fantasy</tag>
		<tag>Encounter</tag>
		<tag>D&amp;D</tag>
	</tags>
	<parameters />
	<supportsMaxLength>false</supportsMaxLength>
	<items>
		<item name="Start">The adventures camp at a hay loft in a small barn. During the night they are awoken as the barn door crashes open revealing two [Giant]s entering to steal cattle.</item>
		<item name="Start">During the night, dark clouds gather and heavy rain starts to fall. Everything gets soaked and cold and each PC must make a survival check or be sickened for 1d4 days.</item>
		<item name="Start">One of the watchers notice a small fire through the woods. If the PCs go to investigate they find a small band of outlaws who will share their meat and mead if the PCs act civilized.</item>
		<item name="Start">One of the watchers notice a small fire through the woods. If the PCs go to investigate they find a small band of [Humanoid].</item>
		<item name="Start">The ingredients in the night's stew turn everyone temporarily [=Pick('bioluminscent','mute','drunk','green')].</item>
		<item name="Start">The party settles in. In the morning, they discover they're inexplicably [=ToText(Roll(4,6))] miles [=Pick('closer to','farther from')] their destination than they thought.</item>
		<item name="Start">Another traveler spots the camp fire and comes in to keep warm. He's as suspicious of the party as they probably are of him.</item>
		<item name="Start">A(n) [Animal] spots the camp fire and comes in to keep warm. It seems to be unwary of the party.</item>
		<item name="Start">Music is heard about three hours before dawn, but no source can be located.</item>
		<item name="Start">The watcher notices a campfire in the distance and as he approaches he appears on the other side of the campsite.</item>
		<item name="Start">The party's campsite is on top of some ancient ruin. If their combined weight gets to or surpasses a certain limit they fall through the roof. They could climb out, but the [Humanoid] inside have a prophecy that their gods will fall from the sky. The party will be treated like royalty, but hopefully learn that the prophecy involves consuming their god as well.</item>
		<item name="Start">A dancing bear! It will be black and brown and covered in hair. If there is a female in the party, he will smell honey and try to lick it from her hair.</item>
		<item name="Start">The party wakes in the morning to find humanoid (Survival check reveals they belong to [Humanoid]s) footprints crisscrossing the camp, evidently leading to all the bunks, mounts, and packs . . . as far as they can tell nothing is missing or has been tampered with.</item>
		<item name="Start">In the night sky over a distant mountain range, the peaks light up as if some great battle of wizards and dragons is raging at the mountaintop, creating a light show that can be seen for a hundred miles in any direction . . . this has nothing to do with the plot that the PCs are working on.</item>
		<item name="Start">The camp is completely besot by a swarm of [=Pick('crickets','grasshoppers','locusts','frogs')], they eat nothing and do no damage, but the noise makes sleep utterly impossible. No rest is gain and spells do not replenish.</item>
		<item name="Start">Around midnight, whoever is on watch makes a Perception check to notice the sound of several small creatures attempting to sneak up on the camp. If not noticed, several 8 to 10 year-old kids from a nearby settlement charge the party with toy wooden swords to "test the group's mettle" (-2 BAB, d2 non-lethal).  It's possible they have mistaken the party for the cause of a more serious problem and are trying to deal with it themselves, and have bitten off more than they could chew. Perhaps they are being stalked themselves by the wandering encounter.</item>
		<item name="Start">Just after the party sets up camp, an old man a few apples shy of a bushel approaches the camp rambling about the horrors he has seen in a war that ended over a hundred years ago. To the first character that addresses him directly, he pulls out an amulet, looks directly at them and hands it over while saying "Good King Barised, as a token of our greatest appreciation for acts of kindness in the recent conflict with our most despicable enemies, please accept this meager gift that our nations may forever be allies."He is in fact just the local beggar and crazy, but the amulet radiates a magic aura. The amulet is of high quality and valuable with an inscription on the back to a neighboring noble. It's also contains a magic trap with a rare and exotic poison for the first person to put it on.</item>
		<item name="Start">Instead of just a standard wandering encounter, there are two of them. They meet just in listening range of the party (or even at the camp) and start to fight it out. [Monster] vs [Monster]. It's up to the party to decide when or if they wish to attack. How often do PCs get into 3-way battles?</item>
		<item name="Start">A raccoon picks your pocket looking for lunch.</item>
		<item name="Start">Some hunters show up and offer to sell the PCs some fresh dinner rather than their trail rations.</item>
		<item name="Start">A tent blows away in the wind.</item>
		<item name="Start">A cold still air encompasses the camp putting out the campfire.  Moments later it dispatches [=Pick('leaving the fire unlit',', the campfire reignites')].</item>
		<item name="Start">Some forest creature sends an injured animal towards the party, and uses their treatment of it to decide how it will treat the party.</item>
		<item name="Start">Dryad one night stand (of trees).</item>
		<item name="Start">A [Fey] stands 10 to 15 feet outside of the campsite watching the PCs but will run if approached.</item>
		<item name="Start">A flock of different type of owls stop on the branches and stare at the PCs.</item>
		<item name="Start">A crow does a fairly good imitation of [=Pick('a dog','one of the PCs')] from some nearby branches.</item>
		<item name="Start">A [=Pick('druid','ranger','dryad','huntsman','tracker','hermit')] shows up and points out that there is a much better camp site 500 feet that away, with a mossy forest floor and a nice thick briar tangle to keep the wind/rain down. Its actually more comfortable and bug free than a cheap inn.</item>
		<item name="Start">A large [=Pick('green','blue','red','yellow','orange','purple','white')] head of flame appears in the fire and implores the party for aid (it is a magic mouth like spell from an imprisoned wizard).</item>
		<item name="Start">A large raven lands in a tree in begins spouting [=Pick('ominous prophesies','warnings','a single word repeatedly','the word "Nevermore." repeatedly')]</item>
		<item name="Start">Wowbagger lands his space ship and approaches a PC. After an annoyingly large number of questions to verify the PC is really the person Wowbagger is looking for, he delivers a long series of offensive insults, then returns to his space ship and leaves.</item>
		<item name="Start">There is a lunar eclipse. When the eclipse reaches totality, a mysterious glow appears behind a ridge of ground several miles away.</item>
		<item name="Start">An enterprising band of rats begin gnawing through the bags containing the party's food supplies. Spell component pouches are also viable targets. If those on watch fail several subsequent Perception checks, the party finds part of its stores gone and risk filth fever if they consume the rest before using purify food and drink.</item>
		<item name="Start">A light scattering of precipitation falls in the night. When dawn arrives, the party sees vast [=(Roll(1,4)+1)*10]' tall mushrooms have popped up all over the area. As the day goes on, the mushrooms begin to release spores which - though harmless in themselves - give concealment to creatures beyond a 50' range.</item>
		<item name="Start">A large bat skims the campsite several times, before finally settling upside down on a convenient perch. The bat can be attacked normally, but if consulted with Speak with Animals it reveals that its master, a local ranger, died yesterday and it is seeking help in providing proper burial. If offered the position of familiar or animal companion after this service is provided, the bat accepts: further, it functions as if its master was 1 level higher than the actual class level for purposes of determining its familiar/animal companion abilities, due to prior experience.</item>
		<item name="Start">In rocky country, there is a distant rattling of stones late one night. It is followed half an hour later by a cacophonous rock slide, but the area of the PCs' campsite suffers no worse effects than some clouds of dust. If the PCs investigate, they find the rock slide has crushed a band of [Humanoid]s who appeared to be gathering to attack their campsite. Remarkably, the rockslide is a coincidence, but the PCs are likely to believe differently.</item>
		<item name="Start">A pair of evil [Humanoid]s come running toward the camp, making no effort at stealth or self-defense. If the PCs are caught off guard, or do anything other than spring an immediate attack, the humanoids rush straight through the camp without a sideways glance, although the smaller one is heard to say in crude Common, "Run, you stupids!" The nature of the pursuit is up to the GM; something imposing and terrifying would be dramatic, but something small and inoffensive, such as a pug dog, can be employed for comedy.</item>
		<item name="Start">A(n) [Animal] stampedes into camp to stomp out the fire.</item>
		<item name="Start">Gyllivickle, a gnomish tinker, has spotted their camp. He has [=Roll(1,20)] mundane items for sale as well as [=Roll(1,3)] minor magic items. He craves news of the area and will repay it with streams of dirty limericks which get worse by the rhyme.</item>
		<item name="Start">Obscured in a hollow near the campsite are 3 massive, leathery eggs, all cracked and empty but recently laid. In the distance the sound of shattering trees draws the party's attention.</item>
		<item name="Start">A small pool of clean water is found, fed by a spring burbling out of stone. The water is sweet with a tinny aftertaste. Drinking provokes a DC 14 Fort save; failure indicates 1d2 days of the Sickened condition while success grants the PC 30' Low Light vision for 1d2 days. If the PC already has Low Light vision it increases by 30'.</item>
		<item name="Start">A great tangle of trees, brambles and nettles appears to have worked stone concealed amidst it. Working hard for one hour to clear this brush reveals the ruined remains of a fieldstone cottage; in one corner is an oven similarly overgrown and within it's hoary depths is a charred, [=Pick('female','male','dog','cat')] skeleton.</item>
		<item name="Start">A quickling darts back and forth through camp, showing off. He can either be attacked, flattered, or challenged to a foot race to drive him away. If ignored, he makes for any loose gear he thinks he can swipe and get away with.</item>
		<item name="Start">As the party slumbers a weird fog of descends on the camp. The brume is pink and purple, smelling of vinegar and brine. It does nothing to the party and has no obvious effect, until breakfast the next morning. All food rations, stores of water or potable liquids and any other mundane foodstuffs have been soured and putrefied. That's when the giant carrion beetles arrive.</item>
		<item name="Start">A [=Pick('badger','ferret','rabbit','wolverine')] decides your backpack is his new home.</item>
		<item name="Start">A [=Pick('spider','scorpion')] decides to crawl into your [=Pick('boot','bedroll')].</item>
		<item name="Start">A Mischievous fey plays some practical jokes on the group. They Awaken the group's pack donkey, and now the donkey is very sassy and won't stop prattling on about various minutia.</item>
		<item name="Start">A ruin along the road contains runes pertaining to a ritualized form of Endure Elements; succeeding in a skill challenge to enact the right grants the participants the benefit of the spell for 24 hours; failure results in the participants being Fatigued for 24 hours.</item>
		<item name="Start">A tangle of vines sing and sway. They can be attacked but they are three assassin vines. Otherwise if they are harmonized with for a few rounds they sway apart revealing a hidden cache of loot.</item>
		<item name="Start">A beautiful song is heard in the distance, from amid a knot of trees; it is too far away for the party to make it out very well but it sounds very alluring. Moments later there's a squawk and crashing tree limbs. This fracas culminates in a blast of flames. Should the party investigate they find the smoldering corpse of a woman with taloned limbs and crow's wings.</item>
		<item name="Start">Distant thunder is heard among the clouds. The thunder increases as the night progresses, culminating in a sudden onset of wind and rain with lightning delivering one shattering crash after another overhead. From time to time, the tiny luminous forms of lightning elementals can be seen playing tag in the thunderheads. Rest under these conditions is impossible, unless magical sleep effects are employed.</item>
		<item name="Start">A character untrained in Survival makes the classic camper's mistake involving poison ivy. Neutralize poison or a good Heal check with the assistance of a healer's kit will prevent the penalties; otherwise treat the character as sickened for 24 hours.</item>
		<item name="Start">One misty night, sinister bestial shapes are seen moving out in the fog. On closer inspection (or after the PCs start blazing away), they are revealed to be [=Pick('sheep','cows','llamas')].</item>
		<item name="Start">The party tries to make camp during a particularly miserable, stormy night. As they struggle to set things up the weather seems to tapper off. They then notice the trees around their camp seem to have moved, providing them with shelter from the storm.</item>
		<item name="Start">The characters set up camp atop a clear hillock. As they settle in, the night sky is suddenly light by cascades of falling stars. Seen by thousands, it becomes the focal event for numerous prophesies and omens, as well as bringing a hoard of treasure seekers looking for lodes of meteoric iron.</item>
		<item name="Start">An enterprising party of [Humanoid|Fey] tries to sneak up on the camped PCs...to STEAL anything shiny they can safely get away with.</item>
		<item name="Start">A hideous cry resounds through the night sky as the shadow of a winged monstrosity briefly blots out moon and stars. It continues onward unless it is attacked or finds large chunks of meat (sleeping) in plain sight. It might attempt to snatch one of the party's mounts.</item>
		<item name="Start">A lonely monster can be heard howling mournfully or sobbing loudly somewhere nearby the campsite in the night, at the site of some past personal tragedy.</item>
		<item name="Start">A drunken [Giant] wanders across the campsite and trips over one of the PCs. It is angry at being tripped (as interpreted through the alcohol), but not otherwise necessarily hostile.</item>
		<item name="Start">Several deer run past the camp, followed shortly by a bear. All the animals ignore the camp (assuming the camp ignores the animals).</item>
		<item name="Start">The party awakes to find the campsite covered in butterflies. Treat as a swarm of butterflies that deal no damage but provide concealment to anyone more than 5ft away.</item>
		<item name="Start">At some point in the night [Humanoid]s sneak in and try to steal the party's horses. They flee if confronted.</item>
		<item name="Start">The party discovers that the clearing they choose to camp in is a fairy circle and transports the party to the first world for the night where they encounter various friendly and unfriendly fey. Needless to say they get no sleep.</item>
		<item name="Start">The party camps on the site of a long forgotten centuries old battlefield. During the night the bones of the animal they had for dinner animate as a skeleton.</item>
		<item name="Start">The night passes completely without disturbance, but as the sun begins to rise and color comes back to the world, who ever is on last guard duty realizes that somehow during the night four men have surrounded the camp and now stand motionless leaning against trees. It is a local farmer and his three sons who are here to collect "rent" for the party's use of the campsite</item>
		<item name="Start">An hour before dusk, a chipmunk scurries through the camp, managing to travel over everyone's bed roll even with people in them. Just as dusk falls, a rabbit scurries through the camp managing to travel over everyone's bedroll and waking light sleepers. An hour after dusk a fox scurries through the camp managing to get every bed roll and waking all but the deepest sleepers. An hour later a sheep scurries through the camp ... . An hour later a large dog scurries though the camp... .An hour later a cow scurries through the camp managing to tread on every bed roll and waking anyone not in a magical sleep and doing 1d3 damage from walking. If the party doesn't move camp feel free to use a bison, elephant, dinosaur ...</item>
		<item name="Start">An old hermit approaches and ask if he can use their fire to make dinner for himself. if the party accepts, he shares useful information about the surrounding area, granting a minor competence bonus to survival/knowledge. if they decline, he leaves peacefully, not wanting to impose.</item>
		<item name="Start">In the middle of the night, a pack of wolves howl at the moon a few hundred feet from camp. The party sentries certainly hear them, and they could awaken sleepers. The wolves don't bother the party unless provoked.</item>
		<item name="Start">The campsite the party chose had clearly been used a few days earlier (stone fire ring with ashes, etc). Half an hour after the party sets up camp, another group of travelers arrives from the opposite direction, obviously annoyed that the party has "stolen their site."</item>
		<item name="Start">In the middle of the night, a CR-appropriate burrowing monster erupts from the ground in the middle of the campsite and attacks.</item>
		<item name="Start">The ghost of a person murdered on the site manifests. It asks the party to give its bones a proper burial so it can rest. If the party complies, it shows them the location of a magic item lost nearby. If they refuse, it attacks.</item>
		<item name="Start">The party beds down only to find that no one can get comfy. Sharp stones and lumpy ground prevent any restful sleep. When someone finally tries to "fix" the ground (by removing the rocks, smoothing the dirt, etc. ) they find that they have in fact camped on a mass grave. The "sharp rocks" are dull weapon points and the "lumps" are bits of armor or decaying corpse.</item>
		<item name="Start">In the middle of the night, any sound the party makes is suddenly accompanied by a visual representation of the sound, as if they were in a comic book. Sleeping members have Z's float from their head, all speech appears in bubbles over the party's heads (even though the party can still hear perfectly), and even the crunch of leaves under their feet is illustrated on boldly colored, appropriately styled text. A short search reveals a tribe of diminutive and infinitely mischievous humanoids has set their sights on the party. The beings are nigh uncatchable, but will leave the party alone in exchange for news of an even more entertaining target and a few shiny trinkets.</item>
		<item name="Start">The PC on watch makes a simple Intelligence 10 check to notice that the stars are positioned completely differently.</item>
		<item name="Start">The PCs awake in the morning to discover a huge cow-like footstep near their camp.</item>
		<item name="Start">A strange howling wind makes everybody unrest. Everybody roll a Willpower save DC 10 against fear, or no rest is possible that night. In the morning, the PCs find that some large trees have vicious claw-like branches and twisted faces.</item> 
		<item name="Start">During full moon, an object covers 1/4 of the lunar surface for half an hour.</item>
		<item name="Start">A pack of feral dogs are attracted by the smell of the PCs' food. They are unfriendly rather than hostile; nevertheless the guards can see hungry eyes peering at them throughout the night. After the PCs break camp they will see the pack nosing around the site for anything remotely edible.</item>
		<item name="Start">Late at night, the distant flap of leathery wings can be heard. Low-light vision will reveal two dragon-like shapes seemingly pursuing each other in lazy loops over the countryside. A Knowledge (arcana) check can reveal that courting wyverns generally engage in a mating flight; they are unlikely to take an interest in the camp.</item>
		<item name="Start">Muffled, cheery singing emerges from the ground underneath the bedroll of one of the party members. Should the party peel back the sod underneath the bedroll, they find a warrior's bones and an axe of greenish metal set with small teardrop-shaped orange stones. The axe is the source of the song: it is a jolly, joking soul with a penchant for song. While the axe's powers (scaled by party level) are useful, it has an unfortunate tendency to sing softly when the party is attempting stealth, make blunt remarks when diplomacy is called for, and tell dirty jokes at court. This is not out of innate evil, just callous thoughtlessness, but this thought has been of little comfort to the axe's many previous owners, all now deceased.</item>
		<item name="Start">Hail storm! Those under the open sky take 1d4 points of bashing damage per round until they seek cover (like a tree or that strange ruin they decided to ignore until morning when they would get all their spells back). Particularly fragile items left on the ground may get damaged or broken. And of course, the mounts will break free in order to seek shelter, requiring someone to go round them up after the storm.</item>
		<item name="Start">Numerous frogs and crickets serenade the party throughout the evening, until suddenly there is a large splash and the entire wetland surrounding the campsite goes ominously quiet.</item>
		<item name="Start">Suddenly there is a flash of light as bright as day and a large metal chest comes tumbling into the camp. Opening the chest (which is latched but unlocked) reveals the amazingly well preserved of some poor adventurer who crawled into the chest and suffocated. The loot on the body consists of an explorer's outfit, a distinctive brimmed hat, and a whip.</item>
		<item name="Start">A distant cantering is heard, and two travelers on severely fatigued horses appear coming along the path at top speed. They pull up next to the fire, and offer to trade the PCs their horses plus a good-sized pearl in return for the two best mounts the PCs care to part with. They are sincere, but extremely evasive about the reason for their haste, and perceptive PCs may note that one is keeping a hard leather satchel at his side very protectively. If the PCs will not trade, the two travelers - with many hard words - guide their weary mounts onward. Half an hour later, a mounted patrol from a nearby town - mistaking the PCs' campsite for that of the thieves who just stole a secret map from their lord's archives - attack their camp: since none of them saw the faces of the thieves, they have no reason to recognize that this is a case of mistaken identity.</item>
		<item name="Start">While hunting up firewood for camp one of the PCs stumbles across a pit in the ground; a [Animal]'s carcass a few day's old rots here. Returning to camp several other, natural traps have been triggered recently before the arrival of the party. There are spiked branches, swinging logs and a stone that was dropped from the canopy. Some of these are coated with a weird, greenish blood that glows. Searching the area with a DC 20 Perception check reveals a strange alien-shaped helmet which keeps whispering the phrase "anytime" and then laughing loudly in a deep, throaty voice.</item>
		<item name="Start">Several of the surrounding trees have lover's symbols carved into them. If the PCs seek out more or show interest in them, the next one contains Sepia Snake Sigil, Explosive Runes, or another writing-based trap.</item>
		<item name="Start">While searching for a campsite PCs find a skeleton in a cold-iron cage, hanging from a dead tree.</item>
		<item name="Start">A pond near camp is surrounded by cattails; each of the stalks has a golden ribbon tied to it save one.</item>
		<item name="Start">An old runestone scorched by lightning can be seen. It radiates no magic yet, as the sun sets across its face, blood-colored "tears" channel through the sigil into the wet ground.</item>
		<item name="Start">Several crows feast on the corpse of an old man in robes with several items usually associated with wizards (a wand, spell components, a spellbook). If the scene is investigated the crows circle, forming a Murder of Crows (swarm) and attack. If they are left to their own devices however, upon finishing their hoary feast they circle into the form of the man's face in the air; the fluttering visage warns of a coming plague.</item>
		<item name="Start">A traveling circus happens by. They entertain the party for money. If they are well treated and tipped they smile and move on; if not they set up an ambush to rob the PCs.</item>
		<item name="Start">The logs the party burns turn the fire crimson and violet. Any who inhale the fumes must save against a mild poison. Close inspection of the wood reveals a rare fungus that is highly toxic and worth a good deal of money in the black market.</item>
		<item name="Start">An eerie moaning comes from the center of the campfire.  If the campfire is extinguished and the logs replaced it does not continue.</item>
		<item name="Start">A sudden flash flood has carried for miles to arrive at the party's campsite at this very moment; unless specifically protected against all of the party and their gear is waterlogged.</item>
		<item name="Start">The person on watch/the sleeping party see a bolt of lighting hit tree a few yards away the tree is on fire and there is a war hammer lodged in the tree anyone touching the hammer takes 1d4 fire damage, the hammer cannot be lifted except by a DC 35 strength check.</item>
		<item name="Start">While setting up camp a group of travelers asks to share the site with them for the night. If the party refuses nothing happens, if the camp is shared the group of travelers dies in there sleep. Upon inspection of the bodies the party finds evidence that one of the men is a prince from a neighboring kingdom.</item>
		<item name="Start">When the party sits around the fire they are surprised to find out that the log they are using as a seat is grumpy and doesn't like to be sat on.</item>
		<item name="Start">While the party is sitting around the campfire, a feral-looking canine sprints from the bushes on one side of camp, leaps over the fire-pit, and dashes off into the woods opposite whence it came. A moment later a lithe humanoid dressed in dark earth-tones and carrying a glowing bow leaps from the same bush and fires in the direction of the canine. He scoffs, "Damn," (apparently missing) and sprints after the beast, ignoring the party.</item>
		<item name="Start">The party finds the long-cold old campsite of a group of clerics of Lamashtu. There are stick figures and effigies hanging from the trees, but it's a well-hidden site. If the party rests there, their tents become animated and start wandering around the landscape making hyena noises. The bedrolls become animated and start making rattling noises, like rattlesnakes.</item>
		<item name="Start">A nearby tree turns out to be a powerful and grumpy treant shedding his acorns. He will not let the party sleep unless they tell him a good story near the campfire.</item>
		<item name="Start">The party watch sees a lone man, jogging at night across the road. He wears a rabbit mask and explains that he's in training. Something feels vaguely uncomfortable about him. If a party member with the endurance feat runs with him for a spell, and can keep up, the Jogging Man hands over his rabbit mask, which operates as Boots of Springing and Stepping but in the headband slot.</item>
		<item name="Start">The party comes across a large stack of wood perfectly prepared to create a roaring inferno of a fire. There are asiatic lanterns hung in the trees. A DC 20 perception check reveals ritual lines carved in the rocks nearby, they are very ancient. If the PCs are foolish enough to light the ritual bonfire to use as a campfire, it summons a Fire Oni that proceeds to march towards the nearest settlement in order to burn the place to the ground. Despite all contrary evidence, the Fire Oni believes the PCs are ancient and powerful evil fire shamans. Despite this, he won't listen to any orders from them.</item>
		<item name="Start">A stranger camps with the party. In return for their hospitality, he tells them a story. The party finds itself in the story. Placing PCs in the "wrong" parts could be played for humor.</item>
		<item name="Start">A distant light appears and begins to approach the campsite. Once it's quite close the PCs get Perception checks to realize that it's not a carried light, but a Small fire elemental. Called inadvertently to this miserably cold and moist dimension, it has been wandering the wilderness for days, setting a number of minor blazes; it has mistaken the campfire for one of its own kind. Seeing its fellow 'held captive' by squashy meat creatures, it attacks the PCs. If the PCs follow its trail (a very simple Survival check), they'll eventually discover a cavern temple inhabited by members of a fire-worshipping cult.</item>
		<item name="Start">While camped in the woods in spring or autumn, the person on watch abruptly realizes that falling blossoms (in spring) or leaves (in autumn) are swirling around, and occasionally coming to rest on, an invisible Medium-sized figure just within the range of visibility. The unseen investigator panics and bolts if the alarm goes up.</item>
		<item name="Start">Late at night, when the fire is just embers, the partially eaten carcass of a herd animal falls from the sky into the camp. All that follows is the distant fluttering of wings far overhead.</item>
		<item name="Start">While gathering fuel, one of the party picks up a dead branch and disturbs a hornet's nest releasing a swarm of hornets.  If the party cannot disperse the swarm they will have to abandon their planned campsite and all their gear, and stay away from camp until night has fully descended and they can slip back without rousing the hornets again.</item>
		<item name="Start">While casting about for a decent place to set up the camp, the PCs come across a level patch of ground with very little undergrowth. Although this site was hallowed a couple centuries before, the wooden shrine that was once on the site is long absent. All creatures in the area benefit from magic circle against evil and death ward, but unless the PCs are attacked that night or employ magic-sensing effects while on the site they might not even realize it.</item>
		<item name="Start">The PC on watch spots a pair of leaves falling from a nearby tree. There is also an audible fluttering but nothing obvious to the senses. A Perception (DC 15) reveals a sprite merily dancing with the leaves on their way down. When they hit the grass he lands gracefully, bows then disappears into the underbrush.</item>
		<item name="Start">A randy member of the opposite gender to an Animal Companion, Familiar or Mount of the party has decided that the time is right to "Make their move."</item>
		<item name="Start">Scouting for a campsite the PCs notice stones piled atop one another in a clearing. Soon they see another such pile. They also begin to notice wicker figures and chimes of bones tied to tree limbs. Finally, near a body of running water, they find a huge, flat rock at the water's edge showing old blood stains and a pair of rusty manacle housings.</item>
		<item name="Start">A young girl with a fanciful swallow on her shoulder asks to join the party's camp one evening. She seems a fine enough companion and she offers some of the liquor in the gourd at her side. She claims to be Biddle, a simple woodland girl. If the party allows her to stay nothing untoward seems to happen and she even tells some stories about the area to make their travels easier (advantage for the next day's Survival checks). In the morning, regardless of PC watches she's gone w/out a trace. Moments after camp is packed up an inquisition arrives hunting a dangerous witch wanted for the disemboweling of 3 townsfolk. She apparently makes wine with the offal and imbibes it from a gourd to aid her powers. The Inquisitor's description matches that of Biddle.</item>
		<item name="Start">One night shortly after midnight, there is a very faint earth temblor - a tiny quake that doesn't do much but shake the foliage and jar the PCs awake. This is not particularly unusual, of course, but the exact same thing happens shortly after midnight for the next four nights as well.</item>
		<item name="Start">A migration of luminous beetles sweeps overhead shortly before dawn. A few dozen of these beetles land near the campsite, crawling over everything and eating anything immobile and edible. The creatures attack only if attacked, and should a means to cage them be at hand - or improvised - they can be employed (or sold to NPCs) as 'living lights' roughly as powerful as a candle.</item>
		<item name="Start">In the midst of a downpour one rainy night, giant frogs hop up from the nearby riverbank. They will opt for the smallest party member, or a familiar, as their first target. Fatigue and the usual penalties of heavy rain complicate the fight, although since the frogs make no effort to concert their strategy, the PCs should still have little difficulty.</item>
		<item name="Start">The PCs note a distant spearhead-shaped light in the sky. This comet will be consistently visible for many nights to come; although it is not significant to the immediate adventure, it will eventually become significant - a new doomsday cult regards the comet as the approaching chariot of a being from the Dark Tapestry.</item>
		<item name="Start">After a quiet night spent under the stars, one of the PCs is awakened by something wriggling under their legs as they stir. A venomous snake, spider or other creepy-crawler has decided that the warmth of the PCs bedroll makes a nice retreat from the cold night air.</item>
		<item name="Start">During the night, the local fey play mischievous but harmless pranks, such as sewing someone up in their bedroll, painting everyone's face blue with berry juice, or dropping dead mice down the back of whoever is awake and on watch. The constant annoyance prevents anyone getting a full night's rest.</item>
		<item name="Start">PCs find a rope, seemingly hanging from mid-air. It is an active rope trick spell and will last another 11 hours after the PCs find it.</item>
		<item name="Start">PCs accidentally trigger a waiting magic mouth, which states in the voice of a harried-sounding old man. “My friend, if you are hearing this, it is likely too late for me and the daemons have found me. The command word is “veris atunkeh”. Raise a glass in my honor on Midsummer’s Eve and know that I go to my grave knowing that you will carry on.” The magic then fades away forever.</item>
		<item name="Start">PCs are in the wrong place at the right time and receive a sending spell. “Our agreement is in jeopardy. The Red Mantis will visit your family if you don’t tell me right NOW what I want to know.”</item>
		<item name="Start">PCs are approached by a young boy in some panic and disrepair. His sister has been bitten by a poisonous snake and sent him to get help. She is [=Roll(1,4)+1] hours away by the boy’s pace, but if the PCs have someone with swift tracking or the ability to get to her magically she is only an hour away via direct route or by magical flight. She is taking 1d3 damage per hour and has [=Roll(2,4)+2] hp remaining when the boy finds the PCs.</item>
		<item name="Start">PCs notice a glint in the firelight of the campfire. It appears that a metal chest containing 15 silver pieces in ancient silver coin was buried in their fire pit. Inside is a weather-worn scroll that reads “As agreed, half now, and half upon delivery of the oracle” in a very old script. The box has apparently been there for years.</item>
		<item name="Start">A local pet sees the camp and comes to investigate. It is friendly and will eagerly accept any food it is given. If the PCs return it to the owner, a nearby hermit, he will be so appreciative of the return of his only friend he will give them a masterwork tool or 1st level scroll that they may find useful. If they leave without seeking out the owner, the animal will follow them for [=Pick(3,4)] miles before falling behind and perhaps becoming lost for good.</item>
		<item name="Start">The PCs find an old shrine decorated with crumbled but still beautiful statues of [Statues] around a fountain that still bubbles with bright pure water, with a small horde of coins worth [=Roll(10,10)] gold at the bottom of the fountain. Attempting to make wishes by dropping money in, nothing happens. However in the morning anyone who has touched the water has transformed into whatever the statues represent. If the afflicted drop their coinage (DM decides how much), they will revert back in 24 hours and lose the bonuses they gained.</item>
		<item name="Start">The PCs find an old shrine decorated with crumbled but still beautiful statues of animals and appears to be druidic in nature. Any animals drinking from the water become permanently awakened.</item>
		<item name="Start">As the party set up camp, they hear a hunting horn in the distance and the baying of hounds. A white deer races through their camp, pauses and says in Common, "Please don't let them catch me!" before racing on. [=Roll(2,6)] rounds later the huntsmen and their hounds appear (they are Evil, whatever they are). If they prevent the huntsmen pursuing the deer, it provides advice for them on their quest, truthfully and completely answering three questions. After the third is asked it can speak no more, but will lead the party to an item that can aid their current quest.</item>
		<item name="Start">An old knight rides up as the party are setting camp, and asks to join them. He is formidable but amiable, and appears to be hunting a magical beast he can never catch.</item>
		<item name="Start">As the party set up camp a particularly bold [Animal+Beast] approaches the camp, acting oddly. If the party does not kill it the creature manages to scratch 'help' into the ground. It's been transformed, but who or why or how it can be helped is up to the DM.</item>
		<item name="Start">Three men, garishly dressed in matching rhinestone costumes and wide-brimmed round hats, arrive at the edge of camp. They gyrate in unison delivering some kind of ritualized greeting. One of them, calling himself "Lucky" asks the party if they know the way to the "Singing Bush." Regardless of the PCs' answer the three friends hurl themselves into the saddles of their horses and ride off.</item>
		<item name="Start">Shortly after setting camp in an out of the way wilderness location, the party needs no perception check to notice a bedraggled, wild-eyed man burst noisily out of the bushes. "What are you doing here?!!!" he wails, "The moon...the MOON!" He runs off into the woods making inarticulate growling noises. It is a full moon. (He thinks he's a werewolf.)</item>
		<item name="Start">In the middle of the night, two small humanoids dressed in green and blue motley and carrying large sacks will run around the camp. Attacks do no damage, but for every strike, a red healing potion is knocked from the sack of the green humanoid, and a blue potion is knocked from the sack of the blue. The blue potion will replenish the last spell cast for any spellcasting class, but must be drunk immediately following the casting. They are nimble little buggers though, and will disappear once three potions are distributed. If the players return to the campground or mention the occurrence at the next town, lawyers will appear bearing cease and desist orders.</item>
		<item name="Start">the PCs awaken to a triggered alarm spell. They find nothing. Did they even set an alarm spell? As the party settles in to sleep, the character with the lowest willpower save is targeted with a sleep spell. [=Pick('All loose gear is taken and buried outside the camp. Perception or survival (track to find it)','any familiars, pets, companions, or small sized party members have been kidnapped and hog tied up the trail a ways','breakfast is made and all bags are packed and saddled with a note left behind saying their security needs work','the "alarm" triggers again a couple more times throughout the night')]</item>
		<item name="Start">somebody talks in their sleep [=Pick('making what sounds like prophecies','in a language no one in the party understands','telling tales of the party's past days','having a dialog with someone the party is seeking')].</item>
		<item name="Start">While moving up the road in an area of wilderness the party happens upon a boy with a peg leg calling himself "Nart." He offers them some minor magic item at a terrible price. If asked where it came from, he claims he "snuck into" a dungeon nearby.</item>
		<item name="Start">A herd of wild cows stands on the side of the road; one of them wears boots. Beneath the cow costume are a pair of goblins, one of whom identifies itself as "La Trine" in a thick accent.</item>
		<item name="Start">The PCs awaken in the morning to find their campsite and the path out lined in skulls; each has a sigil drawn in soot on the brow. None of them radiate magic.</item>
		<item name="Start">The PCs note on their way through the area that this is an area of recent battles and skirmish. Knowledge: Local or History (DC 10) reveals that wizards and rangers were employed on one of the sides to control the battlefields in such skirmishes. If the party continues without much preparation or caution, their path wanders into one of these "controlled" fields; dozens of concealed traps were left behind from the conflict. These traps are CR appropriate; simple covered pits to elaborate crop circle-style explosive runes.</item>
		<item name="Start">Having set up camp in underground caverns, the party is completely surprised by a sudden breach in an underground river (perhaps some time before, they noticed a faint murmur behind a thin wall). Extinguishing the campfire and leaving them in the dark, soaking the party, the room quickly starts to fill with water. [=Pick('','the water isn't lifeless, but contains fierce underwater adversaries','the breach was caused by a light earthquake, which also opened up a new cavern in the ceiling, through which air is escaping - and so may the party','the camp isn't in an isolated cave, but instead the water rushes the party down a dangerous corridor or into a pit')].</item>
		<item name="Start">In the middle of the night, a screaming gnome ranger runs through the camp, swiftly pursued by an enraged giant skunk he horribly botched a wild empathy check on. If rescued he may award the party some minor magic item/potion for their efforts on his behalf. If the party helps the skunk there will be no reward except for a face full of hot stink.</item>
		<item name="Start">Unable to find a decent campsite, the PCs have had to make do with a hollow. A terrible two-day storm strikes; when the winds fade shortly before the third dawn, the PCs discover that they are now encamped on the roof of an ancient ruin exposed by the withdrawal of the landscape.</item>
		<item name="Start">During a midwinter encampment, the PCs hear a strange rumbling-and-crunching in the distance and cries of "hup! hup!" Before long two bands of goblins appear in the middle distance, each straining with all their might to enlarge snowballs which are already over twenty feet in diameter and have incorporated several stones, shrubs, and careless goblins into their mass. For reasons obscure to a non-goblin, these two rival goblin bands have decided to settle a dispute by seeing who can create the largest snowgoblin, and things got a bit out of hand. Each band cries out to the PCs to come help them (they may be evil, but they really need more people Aiding Another on this Strength check): needless to say, taking either side results in a goblin-against-goblin battle royale in the snow with the PCs stuck in the middle.</item>
		<item name="Start">The night passes peacefully, the PCs sleep well.</item>
		<item name="Start">The PC on watch spies a shaft of moonlight filter down, onto something obscured by distance and flora, but despite these complications whatever the light is hitting glows preternaturally.</item>
		<item name="Start">A spectacle of uniquely beautiful butterflies arrives at dusk and settles on one specific tree or perch, ignoring all others.</item>
		<item name="Start">Giant honey bees hum through the area, searching for a field of massive flowers just beyond. They ignore the party unless provoked or the PC is brightly colored.</item>
		<item name="Start">The night goes troubled for the PCs, with dreams filled with terrible nightmares. In the morning, the PCs note that the last PC on guard looks different: spooked eyes, the hair is more whitened (as an effect of aging) and he seems unaware of his surroundings. He doesn't remember anything for last night, but is fatigued.</item>
		<item name="Start">As the players begin to fall asleep they notice a meteor shower in sky. Any player making a DC 20 survival check will realize that the meteors will impact about 2 miles from the camp. If the players investigate they discover that the meteors are actually monsters which have been frozen in ice and fallen from some great height. Although the monsters mostly have died from the freezing and impact, there are two very badly injured trolls among the menagerie and the players have an opportunity to kill them before they grow too strong. If the players do not investigate several hours into the night one fully regenerated troll (he took out the other one) attacks the camp.</item>
		<item name="Start">The camp attracts the attention of cows. Every hour, 1d4+1 more cows arrive, until the entire herd of 28 cattle is milling around the edges of the camp in their bovine way. Shortly after dawn, an irritated rancher appears and asks the PCs to help him get the cows back through a hole in their fence. The amount of money he offers for the help is fair by his standards, but quite insignificant to adventurers accustomed to piles of gold.</item>
		<item name="Start">One of the mounts slips its tether and wanders into the night. An hour or two later it ambles back into view and placidly allows itself to be recaptured. In actuality, the "mount" that came back is a polymorphed creature; concerned that its disguise might not hold up in daylight, it waits for a character to mount, it races off at a full gallop, taking full advantage of its mutable shape to evade pursuit while carrying its victim along.</item>
		<item name="Start">The heat of the fire causes an egg-shaped stone at the fire's edge to crack audibly: on opening, the PCs discover that the interior is a geode with 1d4 gem-quality, uncut quartz or amethyst-stones inside. The usual rules for polishing and cutting gemstones can be used to raise these stones to full market value.</item>
		<item name="Start">Somebody talks in their sleep, And it's actually the verbal components to the highest level spell they still have prepared/know. Target and cause for the sleep-casting are up to the GM.</item>
		<item name="Start">The campfire becomes a tiny fire elemental and begins snarking at whoever is on watch. It probably won't attack unless attacked or attempted to be put out.</item>
		<item name="Start">A panicked [=Pick('goblin','kobold')] rushes in and puts out the campfire before running away screaming.</item>
		<item name="Start">A dryad slaps one of the PCs for breaking a dead limb off of her tree.</item>
		<item name="Start">A graveknight enters the camp and begins whistling a cheerful ditty as he roasts some marshmallows for s'mores. He attacks if the PCs don't have chocolate.</item>
		<item name="Start">A pixie uses a twig that's smoldering at one end to poke another pixie. The two proceed to have an argument that swiftly devolves into a slap-fight, which then takes the rather odd turn of who's better at esoteric trivia from other worlds, before they start having a pranking competition, using the PCs as impartial judges.</item>
		<item name="Start">The BBEG strolls through camp whistling. He is naked as the day he was born. If the PCs are awake, he only gives them a simple howdy-do before continuing.</item>
		<item name="Start">A brownie sneaks into camp, risking the PC on watch seeing him. If he is seen he flees; the encounter is over. If not, he makes off with ALL the liquor the PCs have (again; until he's spotted). Should he manage to swipe every last drop, he turns invisible and then expertly mends every rip, tear, crease and loose button on every piece of gear the PCs have. He also leaves behind a fantastically crafted Small sized wooden mug. It's shaped from Darkwood, Bloodoak, or another valuable wood in the setting; it is braced with a pair of beaten copper rings and handle. The handle is shaped like a beautiful woman, scantily clad, her lips fairly parted with her eyes closed. Should anyone blow into the mouth the handle makes the sound of a Wolf's Whistle. The minuscule tankard is considered a masterwork for the purposes of enchantment.</item>
		<item name="Start">The PCs encamp near a small pond with a highly reflective surface. During the long slow watches of the night, each PC gets a Perception check to notice that his reflection in the pool is acting several seconds prior to the actual PC's shifts, paces, and so forth. This effect - the result of some naturally occurring divination magic - is eerie but helpful; a guard keeping an eye on the reflection gets +20 to Perception checks to avoid any surprise round on encounters that night.</item>
		<item name="Start">The PCs make camp and begin settling down for the night. Unfortunately they happen to be on the belly of an huge giant that is a thousand feet tall.</item>
		<item name="Start">After finding shelter from the wind and rain in the lee of a bluff with an overhanging rock-face, the party sets up camp and nominates sentries as usual. During the night each sleeping PC has the same dream, involving a savage yet beautiful woman wearing ancient tribal regalia, who stares intently at them across a campfire as she speaks in a long-forgotten language. The next day the storm has cleared, and as they each compare their dreams, the morning sun falls full upon the rock face nearby, revealing a panoply of faded, ancient rock-paintings depicting some sort of shamanic ritual.</item>
		<item name="Start">After an exhausting search of the tangled thickets and fungus-infested hollows that passes for a forest here, the PCs find a nice patch of dry, flat ground. Said ground is in fact a group of mimics making themselves appear as carpets of sod.</item>
		<item name="Start">If the PCs are foraging or hunting they come across a patch of rare, wild mushrooms. Knowledge: Nature or Survival DC 18 reveals them to be Vittlebox Sorrels; not only edible but a delicacy. They have a coffee like flavor which is at once bitter and sweet. If the PCs harvest any and eat them, roughly an hour after dinner they hear loud grumbling as a trio of pygmies tromp to the edge of camp and begin hurling mud and obscenities.</item>
		<item name="Start">As dawn breaks a lone crow arrives over camp. As the sun rises, each minute 1d6 more arrive until the area is teeming with them, cawing and waking the entire party. The rest of the day's travel the murder of crows seems to keep pace with the PCs until they either destroy the swarm or cross a stream several miles away.</item>
		<item name="Start">A trio of sprites have gathered several kinds of small, thin pine cones and enjoy how they explode when fire consumes them. They choose midnight to sneak in, put them in the coals, then stoke the embers to have their fun. The PC on watch must roll a DC 15 Perception to notice the prank; otherwise as the sentry's attention is elsewhere suddenly the fire sputters, flares, and explodes loudly for no reason, disturbing the whole camp.</item>
		<item name="Start">As the party is bedding down for the night a wild dog runs up to the edge of camp. It barks insistently, as if pleading with the party. Should anyone cast Speak With Animals it turns out that "Timmy" is stuck in the old well and the dog is looking for help.</item>
		<item name="Start">In the last rays of sunshine as the PCs are still setting up camp a sudden rumbling alerts them. A lone fox darts into camp, looks one of the PCs dead in the eye and screams "Run for your life! They're CRAZY and they're after me!" it then turns and sprints off unless restrained in some way. The rumbling is now accompanied by the sounds of horns. Moments later a herd of centaurs dressed in red coats, tiny hats and accompanied by several Small sized tauric dog-people tramples through camp; one of them shouts out "Tally HO!"</item>
		<item name="Start">The party find a strange building made apparently of very thick leather. It has no door, just an opening into a single large room, with five short passageways leading off, ending in dead ends. In the morning the ground shakes as a giant comes looking for his glove.</item>
		<item name="Start">Foraging in the area of camp one of the PCs finds an ossuary; a small shrine crafted entirely of human bones. This ossuary is like a shelf built into the side of a stony hummock. Close inspection reveals a number of religious symbols - the thing is a marker for a war grave left behind by an ancient people.</item>
		<item name="Start">Upon making camp and assigning watches for the night, one of the sentries will eventually notice (Perception DC 10) something metallic glinting in the moonlight or light from the campfire nearby, possibly under some brambles or in mud at the edge of a pond, depending on where the PCs have camped. Upon inspection the glinting object proves to be an old brass lamp, miraculously uncorroded by age and etched with arcane symbols, and will detect very faintly of magic. Rubbing the lamp elicits no reaction however. The faint magic is the result of a Magic aura spell made permanent upon the item by a huckster magician, who sold it to a foolish adventurer years ago as a 'genuine wishing lamp'. By the time the adventurer discovered the deception, it was too late to catch the huckster, and the fake 'wishing' lamp was thrown away here in disgust.</item>
		<item name="Start">An unexpected windstorm seems to sweep up out of nowhere. PCs using blankets and bedrolls in the open have a 75% chance to lose these items as they are whisked off into the sky, while tents have a 60% chance of collapsing and a 10% chance that part of the tent simply tears off. Flying bracken and bits of greenery forces everybody to shield their eyes: coals are hurled from the campfire and anybody who was downwind of it has a small risk of catching on fire (as do any piles of unattended bedding or other flammables). The ferocious gale drops in strength after a few minutes, but the wind continues strongly for the rest of the night, and the chance of an encounter with some out-of-control flying creature is doubled for any checks made that night. Only determined investigation by the PCs will reveal that this gale was the side effect of a control weather spell; the PCs were not within the area proper, but sudden changes in air pressure brought on by the spell caused uncontrolled freak winds all over the area.</item>
		<item name="Start">While gathering firewood, a PC unexpectedly encounters the rare dire phasmid (walking stick); although ordinarily a peaceable type for a giant bug, it objects to being picked up.</item>
		<item name="Start">During the day of travel prior to camping, the PCs meet travelers on no less than three occasions - all females, traveling in ones and twos. After moonrise, a bonfire starts to burn a couple of miles away. A great drum begins to pound, and male characters feel a trembling, as if a magical compulsion were at hand but no commands were forthcoming: female characters feel no such influence. Cautious investigation reveals that a great moonlit sabbat is in progress, with hags, mortal witches and even a witchfire in attendance. The great drum, made of a giant's skin and played by a night-hag freshly arrived from Hades, is a magical lure ordinarily used by the hags to summon meals/potential husbands; however, its magical properties are not being used at the moment, so there's no more than the sense of uneasiness already noted. Unless the PCs are ready for a fairly epic struggle, they may wish to quietly creep away again.</item>
		<item name="Start">A ball rolls through the middle of the camp followed a few seconds later by some strange metal contraption that is bouncing along after it. Light emits from its head and wiggles like a small dog wagging its tail when it notices the PCs before it goes bouncing off again.</item>
		<item name="Start">A group of squirrels enact a famous play using [=Pick('Common','chirping'))] in the branches of a tree at the edge of the camp.</item>
		<item name="Start">A group of Pixies enact a famous tragedy, as a slapstick comedy.</item>
		<item name="Start">An ogre strolls into camp and asks the party if they have any recipes they'd like to share. (He's actually a charming fellow and a really good cook.)</item>
		<item name="Start">A small owl flies around camp before settling down on one the PCs head. All he says if Speak with animals is employed is "who"</item>
		<item name="Start">A distant smell of roasting meat and vegetables comes to the nostrils of the PCs - far better fare than the PCs have been able to enjoy on the road. After considerable searching, the PCs track the appetizing scent to a tiny hole in a nearby cairn of stones. A door about eight inches tall is built into one side of the cairn. If the PCs attempt to parlay with the occupants, the cairn is a home to [Fey]</item>
		<item name="Start">The forlorn call of a horn echoes across the landscape in the coldest, darkest hours of the night. It is answered by a similar horn of different pitch, from another direction. Though this might cause the PCs to experience some tension, the horn-blowers do not attack... at least, not that night.</item>
		<item name="Start">While encamped in a highly enchanted or haunted region, the PCs see the open approach of a solitary figure in antiquated armor. He hails the camp and says he seeks directions. In antiquated Common, he introduces himself, identifies himself as a legionary in the third regiment of Regent (Name Here), and says he got lost in the mist. A knowledgeable historian in the group can determine that this man is really lost: his home kingdom hasn't even existed for over 300 years. While the PCs are likely to suspect a lie, a trick, or at least that the man is a ghost, he really is just what he seems.</item>
		<item name="Start">While encamped in a highly enchanted or haunted region, the PCs see the open approach of a solitary figure in antiquated armor. When the figure gets within 20 to 30 feet of the camp, it appears to disappear as mist.  Moments later it appears walking away from camp on the opposite side.</item>
		<item name="Start">It rains frogs.</item>

		<item name="Statues">women</item>
		<item name="Statues">men</item>
		<item name="Statues">hermaphrodites</item>
		<item name="Statues">[Monster]s</item>
	</items>
	<imports>
		<import>monsters by type.lib.xml</import>
	</imports>
</Grammar>
